<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Personal on Kassian Sun</title><link>https://blog.kassiansun.com/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Kassian Sun</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.3</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 11:59:11 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.kassiansun.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hugo on Github Pages Returns 404</title><link>https://blog.kassiansun.com/posts/hugo-404-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 11:59:11 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kassiansun.com/posts/hugo-404-github-pages/</guid><description>&lt;p>Although followed the official documentation and got it built correctly, the GitHub page still
returns 404. After some investigation with &lt;code>Branches&lt;/code> and &lt;code>Pages&lt;/code> settings of my GitHub repository,
I realize that &lt;code>built&lt;/code>
means a different thing for GitHub. Since the pages are built by Hugo, GitHub doesn&amp;rsquo;t build the
page anymore (unlike the Jekyll I used before). So the source branch shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be &lt;code>master&lt;/code>, but &lt;code>gh-pages&lt;/code>, after
switching &lt;code>Source&lt;/code> to the correct branch, it works now.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hugo Extended Mode on Github Pages</title><link>https://blog.kassiansun.com/posts/hugo-extended-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 11:35:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kassiansun.com/posts/hugo-extended-github-pages/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I was trying to push this repository to GitHub, by following the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/">Quick Start&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/">Host on GitHub&lt;/a>, GitHub actions failed to build with this error message:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>Error: Error building site: TOCSS: failed to transform &amp;#34;ananke/css/main.css&amp;#34; (text/css). Check your Hugo installation; you need the extended version to build SCSS/SASS.: this feature is not available in your current Hugo version, see https://goo.gl/YMrWcn for more information
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>So the answer is simple, comment the &lt;code>#extended: true&lt;/code> in &lt;code>.github/workflows/gh-pages.yml&lt;/code>, the extended version of Hugo will
support building scss/sass. The official documentation didn&amp;rsquo;t mention any on this configuration, so I guess this is a too simple
question to mention on the document, just a commented line of correct configuration should be good enough to let people know this.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello Word</title><link>https://blog.kassiansun.com/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 11:03:54 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.kassiansun.com/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yes, this is my first post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently I&amp;rsquo;m reading &amp;lt;Own Your Tech Career&amp;gt;, the idea of the book is great.
Although I don&amp;rsquo;t know the author personally, we share many same thoughts on technology, career, and life.
The most important thing I learned is how to get engaged in communities &amp;amp; build a personal brand. One thing is
writing personal blogs, so here it is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To be honest, I didn&amp;rsquo;t create this website by blindly following another guy&amp;rsquo;s idea. Since 2019, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy
writing a lot of notes &amp;amp; diaries on OneNote. The goal of OneNote is to build a personal knowledge network, so
it will be easier for me to handle the flood of information and make better decisions. The OneNote focuses on
&amp;ldquo;core&amp;rdquo; technologies and interesting &amp;ldquo;residuals&amp;rdquo;, then the first issue arises: what about those not-that-interesting
stuff? How to tune a specific Nginx configuration, how to write a correct layout in CSS, and some trivial issues
while learning some new technologies (Jetpack Compose, SwiftUI, Rust, Erlang, Haskell, etc.).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>